Announcer: Monday, Monday Monday open wide dev
fans yet ready to stuff your face with JavaScript
CSS loadmodule BBQ tip yet workflow breakdancing
soft skill web development hasty Yes, the crazy
Yes, the tasty web development traits coming in
hot here is where Sarah CUDA, Bob and Scott El
Toro long toilet ski.
Scott Tolinski: Oh, welcome to syntax on this
Monday hasty treat, we're going to be talking
about logging. Logging is something that well, we
sometimes do just to debug, and many times people
overlook the usefulness of having really good
logging within your application inside of both
production and development environments. So my
name is Scott Tolinksi. I'm a developer from
Denver. And with me, as always, is Wes Bos
Wes Bos: way weigh in. Not too much I have I've
been sort of taking my like logging a little bit
more seriously, in the last couple of months, just
because I had some like Gremlins in my app that I
couldn't figure out like, where it was coming from
and what would even cause this request and
whatnot. And like, I just didn't have enough
insight into like, it wasn't errors, or crashing
or anything, it was just like, couldn't figure it
out, you know. So we'll talk about like, what that
is. So I sort of went through and updated my
logging. I'm still not like, some of the stuff in
this episode where I talked about I'm not using
it. I'm mostly still just a console logger. But
we'll yeah, let's get on into it. Yeah. Let's talk
about our sponsor today, which is Sentry, Sentry
is the air and exception, they do so much more of
that they do performance, they do pro filings, and
now they are getting into session replay, which
will allow you to literally see what the user had
done in your application to to trace through
what's going on. So it's actually kind of funny
that we talk about logging, because a lot of the
stuff that Sentry does makes it so that you don't
necessarily have to piece together logs. And we'll
talk about what the difference is between those
types of things. But check it out at Sentry dot i
o use coupon code tasty treat that is going to get
you two months for free. Thank you Sentry for
sponsoring sick. All right, let's get into it.
What do you want to give us a start up? Like why
and what is logging? Yeah, so
Scott Tolinski: as you know, at its very most
basic, everybody has probably tossed a console log
into their code at some point to output something
either on the client side log or your server side
log. And these can be used primarily, you know, we
often just throw it in for a quick debug or
something like that. But you also probably have
seen logging from other frameworks or other things
that you've used, where you're automatically just
getting some things coming in on your your console
explaining what's happening, maybe at some given
point, maybe it's explaining the requests that are
coming in, maybe it's just saying, oh, you know, a
message came in at this time or whatever. It
depends on what system and what type of logging is
enabled in this types of things. And in many, even
like CMS has have, like baked in logging as well
outside of the JavaScript context. But in at the
end of the day logging is basically giving you
visibility to some action that is happening on
your server or your client, depending on how
you're doing this. But it's very most basic. It's
a console log. It's a I got here. But yeah, it's
more complex. It's a, a get request was hit to
this specific URL at this time. And it took this
amount of seconds to resolve or did not resolve or
whatever.
Wes Bos: Why might you want to log something. Logs
are often helpful as sort of a treasure trail to
figuring out what happened if you need to,
everywhere from just view the developer needing to
figure out okay, well, that shouldn't have
happened. Or I need to figure out why somebody
specifically hit this URL with what data and it
caused them something, you can log out that
information, if you just want to see what
endpoints are being hit with what specific data
you can log that, or something just as simple as
like an email was specifically sent. Well, we'll
go a little bit more into the different types of
logging. So it helps piecing together things helps
us find ability. Worst case, I've certainly not
had to do this before, thankfully, but I've heard
of things crashing databases going down whatever.
And often developers have to they don't have the
data of like maybe 10,000 sales went through, they
can sometimes piece that information back
together, or at least the important bits via logs
because they can parse out their logs and recreate
that data in the database.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah. And also, just to be clear
logging is not just for debugging, but also just
for general information and understanding of
what's going on. Right. So, yeah, you say, how is
this different than error handling? Because
basically, in regards to that same bed, how is
this different than just errors and what's going
on in your application? Sometimes it's a little
bit also, at the same time, more targeted and less
targeted, because you can have less targeted info
being logged, letting you know exactly what's
happening around what are potential errors, but
just what's happening in general. But also, you
can have more targeted to situations where you
think that there is going to be an error or could
be an error to give you more context into what
could be happening in that given instance?
Wes Bos: Yeah, yeah, like I just, I just opened up
my logs right now. And I'm seeing people, it's
kind of interesting, you are seeing people go
through the process of visiting the website,
adding a course buying the course checking out
adding a coupon, getting the email being sent,
then the email being the link in the email being
clicked an account being created. Somebody
starting to view a specific video, and then
progress on that video being you can see all of
that in your console, as it goes through. And I
specifically had an issue where people were going
to have magic links in my email, and people were
going to magic links. And the idea of the magic
Link was always undefined. It was the correct
magic link. And immediately after it was
undefined, and I could not for the life of me
figure out what was triggering this undefined
request, you know, like, it's not an error. It
actually it was causing no issues to anybody
except there was an undefined request in my log,
and I could not figure it out for Life Media.
Finally, finally trace it, trace it down. And you
know, what it was, what it was an image tag to
end, the source of the image was undefined. And it
was trying to just, I guess, when you have an
image tag, it tries to request the current URL as
the source. And that was triggering, because I had
like a catch all path setup for the ID in the URL.
It was, it was catching that one as well. And
literally, the the image pass, so I went into my
template, and I go, Oh, I had like a typo in my
template. And I fixed the image tag and whatnot.
But that was driving me crazy. And it was only
until I added additional logging. To see like,
okay, like, is somebody being malicious here? Is
this coming from the same user? Is it like a
browser extension, something like that, I had a
whole bunch more log in, then I was like, Okay, I
see what's happening here. And then I went through
a template. And
Scott Tolinski: it's funny. This just how much
logs can both pollute and save your bacon
sometimes, you know, sometimes, if there's too
much logging too much noise, you can, you know,
over certain things. But you know, part of what is
good about having logging is that, you can often
go ahead and paw through the logs in a more
structured and organized way. So you know, too
much information isn't necessarily a problem. So
what should you log here? I'm going to tell you
what we log. And then we can maybe talk a little
about what you should log. But you know, I think
personally, what I like to see in a log is I like
to see, you know, what type of what is I'm talking
like server side logging here specifically? Yeah,
one like really important thing about log is the
timecode, in which this thing happened. Because
without having the time in which something
happened, you going back and referencing it is
kind of pointless, right? You'd say at some point,
in some time this, this event happened. But if you
knew when an event happened, specifically, maybe
an error on your site or something happened,
right, and you want to investigate, so you're
piling into the logs, having that time code that
says this happened at this time, really important
to be able to nail down exactly when scope when
that happened. You know, also, I like what type of
request it was a get post put whatever. I like the
path that was requested. I like the total time of
the response. I like those types of things in my
logs. I also like to know what type of log this
is, is this an information log? Is it an error? Is
it and these can things these things can be color
coded accordingly, so that an error log could have
a red error or something so that way when you're
looking at your logs, the errors stand out in the
information once kind of hide back or any of those
types of things.
Wes Bos: Oh, that's a good idea. I so I'm half
excited to do this episode just so I can do a
little bit of improving on mine. cuz maybe we
should talk about that specifically, like, how do
we log right now. So right now what I'm doing is I
just had like different areas of the application.
So whether it is a magic URL it whether it's a
login, whether it's a progress update, whether
it's somebody has invited somebody to their team
account, so they can go in on it, whether somebody
has changed their email, all that type of stuff.
And I just basically have like a, an ID or a name
for each one, like I put it in square brackets,
just magic. And then I put some information along
in there. So things like URL, maybe query
parameters, maybe body parameters, if it's a form,
submit other information about stuff that you
specifically need you unfortunately, at least I
don't think you can't log the entire request
object, because that would be absolutely massive,
and your logs will get pretty large quickly. But I
think, I don't know, do people do that? Do they
log the entire request?
Unknown: I can imagine, that seems like way too
much text for everything. That seems like that
would never work in a large context, right? No,
because you would be like,
Wes Bos: I certainly have had, like log files,
we'll talk about what to do with these log files.
But I've had log files get into the gigs and gigs
I've once very early on, when I was just logging
to log files on my server, I could not figure out
why every couple of weeks, the server would slow
down until I rebooted it. And finally, I realized
is because I was using forever, and forever will
put your logs in a log file. And then when you
restart it, I think it deletes it or something
like that. And I was running out of space on my
server. Yeah. And it was just getting slower and
slower, because there's like not enough space to
run things. And then when I cleared out the logs,
they would go and that's why you have to have sort
of a better approach for this type of stuff.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, I've certainly gotten the
email that says your server space is limited.
Because you're running out of space. And to only
be like, Wait, how is that possible? Oh, wait, let
me go check that law. Oh, boy. Yeah, big O logs.
And if you're logging every request that way?
Yeah, we often forget, as developers that like
text is bytes. Eight, you're saving a lot of text
or a lot of information. Yeah. And that's, it's
pretty easy to rack up actual storage space of of
things with just text just by writing a lot of
text.
Wes Bos: Yeah, you get 100,000 requests a day, and
you're, you're logging a couple lines for every
single person. Those add up pretty quickly.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah. Okay. So one thing I also
wanted to mention that I do, just for fun for our
information logging, especially in our requests, I
do it a little emoji based on how like long or
short, the total response time was. So I start
counting, when the request comes in. And then I
stopped counting when the response is going out
just via middleware. And I measure that time. And
if that time is really fast, you get a rocket
ship. If it's shorter, you get a bunny rabbit. And
if it's really long, then you get a turtle. And
I've been I've been thinking about expanding this
a little bit more. But it's really simple just to
see a turtle a rabbit or rocket ship in your logs,
it makes it like for me, just really visual in
terms of alright, I'm working on this one
component. And I've been seeing a ton of turtles
in development. Why am I seeing so many turtles in
this specific route, but not others?
Wes Bos: That's awesome. What else should you log
descriptive messages about what happened? So not
just login attempted but login attempted with user
email address, obviously, don't put passwords in,
in your logging in, maybe we should talk about
that really quickly is logging personal,
personally identifiable information, you certainly
start get to step into areas of GDPR, and all
these rules around private information and
tracking or whatnot. So you certainly make sure
you are up to date with all of that as well as
scrubbing the logs as part of when somebody does
request to be deleted from you, you have to think
about oh, like, of course you have the user and
purchases and things like that. But you probably
also have information about maybe you have that in
a log somewhere that also should be scrubbed.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah. I mean, it's important to
know that it could just become another attack
vector. So if you do have something that is
secure, needs to be secure in your log, and
someone get x gets access to your logs, then
that's as bad as you know, them getting access to
the information itself. Because yeah, that
information is sitting there.
Wes Bos: Or even like other employees that
shouldn't necessarily have access to that
information. You put all this work in permissions,
you have to be careful that you're not putting
anything in the logs that other employees could
have access to. Yeah, especially if it's insulting
to those other employees. Yeah. So we'll talk
about like, what about Like development, staging
production. A lot of people, I don't specifically
do this, I really only just log stuff that I think
I might need. But you can set different levels of
logging. It goes from like error warning, all the
way up to verbose and silly, where you sit, you
literally log absolutely everything. And that can
be actually really helpful. Specifically, like I
know with ES lint, es lint has like a, a silly
mode or verbose mode where it will log every
single thing that it's doing. And that could be
helpful to follow the request along, like at a
certain point, that's also what breakpoints are
for in your code base. But it can be nice to Nice
to see what it is doing.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, I mean, there are times when
you just dump them in, to try to get it to get
some visibility to what's going on, especially in
development. But in production, you know, yeah, I
pretty much keep most of my normal, like
informational logging in production, like, it's
really helpful to be able to see, all right, a get
request came in, you know, this, this is just at a
glance is like is what's going on in the site. But
also, at a glance, even though I do use tools to
the evaluate my speed of the site, it's really
nice to see at a glance in the locks, the emoji
that I put in there just for fun, and these are
only server side. So it's not like these are, you
know, polluting the client side logging experience
or anything like that, which, honestly, you know,
your site probably shouldn't be outputting too
many things to the client in production. Unless
you're, you know, trying to have fun with it, but
you got to kind of remove some of that stuff,
Wes Bos: I leave probably more than I should in my
because sometimes I get emails from people, and
they'll show me their console. And I'm like, Well,
I'm kind of glad I stuck that in there. But on the
same breath, this is not part of the sponsor. But
one thing that I really like is if you do have an
error in that goes into your Sentry, or whatever.
Sentry has this thing called breadcrumbs, which
will it will show you like which functions were
called up to the error. But any thing that you
console log will also be included in the
breadcrumbs. And that I found is very helpful,
because you can see, and then I like when I was
having an issue with a specific thing. The other
day, I went in and added more logging. And then I
go to the breadcrumbs. Okay, okay, now I have a
little bit more insight into to what is happening.
So that was super handy, too.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, we often talk about the name
of the game being visibility, and debugging,
right, knowing what you're trying to fix. Yeah.
And that's just really where logging comes into
play here. And one thing I really love seeing come
into my logs is that somebody tried to access WP
admin and got it.
Wes Bos: Yeah, that's the other thing is like bot
logs as well. So bots will try to hit common
endpoint spots will try to submit forms with with
random data. I had a bot the other day tried to
submit a bunch of like Postgres SQL injections
into a form. And it's hilarious because I don't
use Postgres literally anywhere. So that wouldn't
have worked. But like, it's not somebody sitting
there trying to do it. It's, it's a bot trying? I
don't know, I think I think it was something like
it went on for about six or seven hours until I
until I jumped in and go Oh, like this form should
probably have have a CAPTCHA on it so that the bot
can't do that. But it was kind of funny watching.
The requests come in every two seconds with the
new piece of information that they're sent in. And
they don't do it. They do it just enough that it
doesn't hit any, like throttling. Yeah, rate
limiting that. So that's another thing you should
be logging is any throttling or rate limiting that
happens in the app level? You can log that to show
but the bots are smart enough to figure out what
is the limit for this website. And even if it
takes six days to get all of the possible combos
through, they can do that.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, I actually, it's funny. I
was just writing something the other day to do
like automating browser tasks. And I had a little
set timeout in a loop because I knew that if I
didn't Yeah, then it would get hit by the rate
limiting. So I was just like, alright, if I set
this set timeout loop to be 200 milliseconds, all
right, it fails after the first one, I set it to
300 fails or 400 succeeds. Alright. 400 is my
number. So you can like dial in exactly what the
rate limiting is.
Wes Bos: Let's talk about where to put logs. So at
the very basic, either your service will handle
the logs for you, they'll stream them in and you
can just go to logs in the dashboard. Or if you're
just on like a like a like a straight up VPN or
VPS server Linode Digital Ocean something like
that will generally have log files in there that
you can. You can go in and download and whatnot.
Generally these log files are massive. so they
they can't, you can and like, back in the day, it
used to be hard to just open them up in your text
editor. Text Editors are very good at opening up
files that are two gigs and searching through them
now. So it's not so much of an issue. But most
services that do hosting will allow you to do
what's called log drains, meaning that okay, we'll
keep logs for we'll keep the last 10,000 logs, or
we'll keep the last week worth of logs. And then
after that they're deleted, because at some point,
you should, you shouldn't keep logs around for
that much longer. But if you do need to keep them
for a little bit longer than you have to port them
into something else. So whether that is as simple
as a text file on AWS, or there's lots of services
out there that are specific log drains, and they
are really helpful because you can do things like
search for specific words, you get syntax
highlighting, you can filter sorting filters, or
all that type of stuff and graphs and all Yeah, I
don't do any of this. Because sometimes I look at
the the prices of these things. I'm like, I don't
know, another 22 hours a month for something like
this, you know, but I look at it like specifically
is one better stack? Log tail looks nice.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, log tail is great. You know,
I've used I've used log tail, I've used paper
trail. Those are two of the big ones. Some of the
other ones are sumo logic log DNA logs.io,
sematext, logs, data, dog has logging logic
monitor has logging Dynatrace has lot like there's
a lot, right? Yeah, this is like a big a big thing
where some of these do more than just logging,
right? But, you know, we're talking, the big boys
for just straight up locking log tail and paper
trail are probably the two biggest ones. I've used
both of them, both of them, you know, they were
great to have, especially as diagnostic tools when
you were looking for, like a specific instance
that happened, I found it to be way easier to find
specific instances or specific issues, or really
dive into the logs a little bit more with these
tools. But at the end of the day, like you said,
they're they're just kind of unneeded expenses for
our level of what yeah, what we're working with,
you know, I can dive into the log files, no
problem and still get access to the same
information. So I probably shouldn't be paying a
service just to be making it a little bit easier.
But if I was on a big project with a big team with
more requests than what I'm dealing with right
now, I think something like this would be
essential. I just I you know, I don't need it for
our size. So
Wes Bos: when you actually go ahead and log, I
said earlier, I'm simply just using straight up
console log. But there are lots of other packages
that will do these for you. Winston is the big one
that's usually included in Express apps and no GS
base. They allow you to do different types of logs
and pass context to it and all kinds of good stuff
like that. I've never liked that because I liked
the idea of that. But I hate having to import a
package in every file, which it's I think, maybe
less of an issue now with the auto import and VS
code. So maybe I should take another look, do you
use a specific package.
Scott Tolinski: I always used a Pino before pi n o
from you know, the awesome Matteo Kalina. And this
was the one I used to because it came with FASTA,
phi, and Mercurius. And I really like it. There's,
it's a really, it's really robust, it does a lot
for you. low overhead, it's, uh, overall, a super
nice logging package. But, you know, I would
probably, instead of trying to use this in a
sense, where you're dropping in like a console
log, if something like this, like a service, I
would probably try to like intercept, intercept
errors or intercept requests and do this in more
of like a middleware type of way. And then just
use straight up console log everything else, I
Wes Bos: guess. Oh, yeah. Yeah, that makes sense.
We should do a show on middleware. I don't think
we've ever done that.
Scott Tolinski: Yeah, I just wrote a little
middleware that I added to it. I had been using
Intel kit to automatically parse foreign data from
our forms and make them just available and spell
kit form action.
Wes Bos: I saw that you published it. Yeah, I
Scott Tolinski: published it. It's like I've had
this thing in my codebase for a little while. I
actually have a few of those. Like, I have a spell
kit logging one and I have our it's like, Hannah,
she did take me a couple of minutes to put this up
live somewhere. So yeah,
Wes Bos: yeah, I specifically the one thing that
has gotten me with the middleware I use tons of
middleware, but I never like I wish that the
TypeScript types would update for requests that
are after the middleware, you know, like before
the middleware you know that it's not going to be
there and after the middleware and like, wherever
they are, they you always have to do like an if
statement to check if it's specifically there,
which is probably better type practice, but it
would be nice if somehow you could You would know
if the middleware was run before and it's kind of
hard because you don't know the functions where
they are, you know? Yeah, totally. But But well,
we'll throw that on the Bucks middleware. What's
coming up? What else do we have here about logs?
Scott Tolinski: I think that might be it. Yeah,
Wes Bos: I think that's it. It's helpful to log
log stuff that you think you need put them in,
because sometimes you're going to need that
information after and you realize, oh, shoot, I
probably should have had better logging in place.
So take a take a couple of minutes and maybe add
some better logging to your app. Yeah,
Scott Tolinski: absolutely.
Wes Bos: All right. Thanks for tuning in. Catch
you on Wednesday. Bruce, who's
Scott Tolinski: head on over to syntax.fm for a
full archive of all of our shows. And don't forget
to subscribe in your podcast player, or drop a
review if you liked this show.