[SPEAKER_01]:  browsers you're supporting. It's pretty simple. And I was actually surprised the other day. I found
[SPEAKER_01]:  something that did not work without a vendor prefix still. What was it?
[SPEAKER_01]:  Yeah, it was... Does the scroll bar stuff work without a vendor prefix?
[SPEAKER_01]:  I think it does, or maybe it's custom. I know the input type of range still requires custom
[SPEAKER_01]:  things. But that's not a vendor prefix. I made a tick talk about it one sec. Let's let's pause this a sec.
[SPEAKER_01]:  Oh, it was, it was the CSS gradient.
[SPEAKER_01]:  You have, you have to use dash webkit mask
[SPEAKER_01]:  instead of just straight up mask.
[SPEAKER_01]:  And it's, it's hilarious because even Firefox supports
[SPEAKER_01]:  the, the webkit prefixed version as well.
[SPEAKER_01]:  Because so many people are just doing that.
[SPEAKER_01]:  They're like, oh, you forgot to put the regular version on.
[SPEAKER_01]:  But so every browser, including Safari, Firefox, whatever,
[SPEAKER_00]:  Yeah, you know, vendor prefixing for CSS is certainly something that was of a time for anyone out there who remembers the CSS3 please and any of that stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]:  When for a very long time and for, you know, many years in the start of my development career, CSS hadn't seen any major improvements and it was kind of like a done thing.
[SPEAKER_00]:  It was like, this is CSS, right?
[SPEAKER_00]:  But then when CSS3 dropped, we got all these new features,
[SPEAKER_00]:  the browser prefixes and all that stuff,
[SPEAKER_00]:  and then that really is what exploded the need
[SPEAKER_00]:  for tools like SAS, because now all of a sudden
[SPEAKER_00]:  you have these great new features,
[SPEAKER_00]:  you have browser support that's kind of all over the place,
[SPEAKER_00]:  you put in a tool intermediary to there.
[SPEAKER_00]:  And then as the web has evolved, we've gotten more and more CSS properties,
[SPEAKER_00]:  but it's also gotten more and more dialed in in terms of
[SPEAKER_00]:  any of that stuff at all.
[SPEAKER_00]:  And then that's why you do end up using a tool like Post-CSS to say,
[SPEAKER_00]:  you know, just just...
[SPEAKER_00]:  you know, post compile my CSS or just compile my CSS,
[SPEAKER_00]:  take care of anything I might have thought about
[SPEAKER_00]:  or not, you know, based on whatever browsers
[SPEAKER_00]:  I need to support and just do it.
[SPEAKER_00]:  Sort of like Babel, right?
[SPEAKER_00]:  Where before Babel came out,
[SPEAKER_00]:  you were having to like really think about,
[SPEAKER_00]:  well, Babel came out pretty early in the scheme of things,
[SPEAKER_00]:  but it's basically allowing you to target
[SPEAKER_00]:  specific browser versions to make sure that stuff supported.
[SPEAKER_00]:  But what's cool about Post-CSS, in addition to that aspect of things, is that there's
[SPEAKER_00]:  just a whole plug-in ecosystem, so you can add plugins for specific CSS features that
[SPEAKER_00]:  are yet to come individually, as well as supporting things like prefixes or removing
[SPEAKER_00]:  unused code or all sorts of things, even changing the language of certain things.
[SPEAKER_00]:  I personally do use Post-CSS even though I don't use a CSS or SAS, SAS-CSS or SCSS or
[SPEAKER_00]:  any of that stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]:  But I do use Post-CSS today, no matter what, pretty much on every project, just to get
[SPEAKER_00]:  a baseline coverage.
[SPEAKER_01]:  So first one we have here is variables.
[SPEAKER_01]:  We've talked about this quite a bit.
[SPEAKER_01]:  Variables are extremely well supported.