is auto prefixer. It will add in the vendor prefixes that are required based on which
browsers you're supporting. It's pretty simple. And I was actually surprised the other day. I found
something that did not work without a vendor prefix still. What was it?
Yeah, it was... Does the scroll bar stuff work without a vendor prefix?
I think it does, or maybe it's custom. I know the input type of range still requires custom
things. But that's not a vendor prefix. I made a tick talk about it one sec. Let's let's pause this a sec.
Oh, it was, it was the CSS gradient.
You have, you have to use dash webkit mask
instead of just straight up mask.
And it's, it's hilarious because even Firefox supports
the, the webkit prefixed version as well.
Because so many people are just doing that.
They're like, oh, you forgot to put the regular version on.
But so every browser, including Safari, Firefox, whatever,
supports just regular mask.
But for whatever reason, it's never been unprefixed in Chrome.
There's probably a good reason behind it, but it seems a bit silly.
Yeah, you know, vendor prefixing for CSS is certainly something that was of a time for anyone out there who remembers the CSS3 please and any of that stuff.
When for a very long time and for, you know, many years in the start of my development career, CSS hadn't seen any major improvements and it was kind of like a done thing.
It was like, this is CSS, right?
But then when CSS3 dropped, we got all these new features,
the browser prefixes and all that stuff,
and then that really is what exploded the need
for tools like SAS, because now all of a sudden
you have these great new features,
you have browser support that's kind of all over the place,
you put in a tool intermediary to there.
And then as the web has evolved, we've gotten more and more CSS properties,
but it's also gotten more and more dialed in in terms of
how these things are being added to the browser.
So now we're not having to think so much about prefixes.
But the problem there is that then becomes people just aren't thinking about
any of that stuff at all.
And then that's why you do end up using a tool like Post-CSS to say,
you know, just just...
you know, post compile my CSS or just compile my CSS,
take care of anything I might have thought about
or not, you know, based on whatever browsers
I need to support and just do it.
Sort of like Babel, right?
Where before Babel came out,
you were having to like really think about,
well, Babel came out pretty early in the scheme of things,
but it's basically allowing you to target
specific browser versions to make sure that stuff supported.
But what's cool about Post-CSS, in addition to that aspect of things, is that there's
just a whole plug-in ecosystem, so you can add plugins for specific CSS features that
are yet to come individually, as well as supporting things like prefixes or removing
unused code or all sorts of things, even changing the language of certain things.
I personally do use Post-CSS even though I don't use a CSS or SAS, SAS-CSS or SCSS or
any of that stuff.
But I do use Post-CSS today, no matter what, pretty much on every project, just to get
a baseline coverage.
So first one we have here is variables.
We've talked about this quite a bit.
Variables are extremely well supported.